Wash It
All Away
Episode 8    That Was Too Impressive
Grand Bath
The rush of online orders suddenly
died down after about a week.
I wonder if it was just
some kind of passing fad.
It's so cold! And sweet.
And the lounge is so roomy!
It is nice to get out and try
a different public bath sometimes.
I-I'm sorry for being so late.
Hmm?
Look, I told you we needed to go
scouting first thing in the morning.
We gotta be in Shikoku
by tomorrow morning.
Th-That was my mistake.
I am truly sorry about this.
They will be closing soon, though,
so please wait just a little longer.
The city's last coordinator
was a lot more reliable.
I am so sorry.
Do you think we have enough time?
Well, we'll have to make it work.
The water was perfect!
Thank you very much.
Hey! You spilled it on me!
I-I'm sorry!
I, uh, wasn't paying attention.
I'll wipe it off immediately.
Um, that would be a bad idea!
Huh?
I'll get something for it.
Please wait a moment.
Who was that?
If you spill coffee, don't panic.
Wet a tissue with soap and water
and after you have soaked the stain,
hold a towel or handkerchief
under the stain
and push down from the top with another
dry tissue to squeeze out the moisture.
It should come right out.
If you panic and start rubbing it,
it will stain, so please be careful.
O-Okay.
There. Your shirt should be fine now.
Th-Thanks a lot.
Ah... um...
I run a cleaning business nearby.
My name is Kinme.
I'm used to dealing with things like this.
Th-Th-That was too impressive!
I... I would love to learn
how to be that resourceful.
Uh, well...
I forgot to introduce myself.
I work at city hall
in the Tourism Economy Division.
My name is Hatsuayu Uka.
Atami City Hall
Tourism Economy Division,
Tourism and Construction Department
Office for the Promotion of Tourism
Location Coordination and Assistance
Hatsuayu Uka
1-1 Chuo-cho, Atami, Shizuoka
A location coordinator?
Yes.
I provide information about
location facilities for TV and movies
and help coordinate shoots.
The guy said we can go in now,
so we're gonna get started.
Ah, okay.
Thank you very much. Goodbye.
Working this late? It must be a tough job.
Nikko-tei
Grand Bath
Kinme Cleaning
Yes. I believe I can
work with this material.
You can? Thank goodness!
Then I'll leave it in your hands.
Sure!
You can count on Kinme.
You always do come through.
Gift Shop
Atsuei Dried Fish Shop
Atsuei Dried Fish Company Direct Sales
Atsuei Gift and Souvenir Shop
Oh, that reminds me.
I decided to try that other bath house.
It's a little far, but it is really nice.
Is it? Perhaps I'll take
Nairo-chan there sometime.
Definitely! Well, I should get going.
Ah!
Is there anything I can
help you with today, Hatsuayu-san?
Uh...
Tha...
Thank you so much for the other day.
I'm sorry. I just really wanted to see
how you work with customers up close.
I've always been super bad at
communicating with people and stuff.
I got a job at city hall thinking
I could do office work behind the scenes,
Atami City Hall
Tourism Economy Division,
Tourism and Construction Department
Office for the Promotion of Tourism
Location Coordination and Assistance
Hatsuayu Uka
but then I got assigned to the Tourism
Economy Division as location coordinator.
It's a job for someone who is resourceful
and has excellent communication skills.
Get permission
from the hotel for that shoot.
Can you handle the lunches for the crew?
I'd like to change
the actor's accommodations.
Please get us clearance to use that road.
Don't you know of a good hole-in-the-wall?
We're looking for a restaurant
for our cooking show.
How can I get in touch with local extras?
So I'm always s-stressed out
about all that,
but when I saw you jump into action
with such great social skills...
B-Basically, I wanted to ask you,
what's the trick to being good at
a job that depends on client relations?
What's the trick? Hmm.
Hmm.
If it's okay with you, why not
join me at the public bath tonight?
Huh?
Welcome
Open
Business Hours From 2 p.m. to 9 p.m.
Hot Spring Bath
Atami Station Front
Station Front
Hot Spring
Okay, Kinme-san. Catch you later.
Oh! Have a good night!
Good evening, Kinme-san!
Today sure was a hot one!
I feel completely drained.
Good evening.
Yes, I was sweating all day long.
D-Do you come
to the public bath often, Kinme-san?
Yes, I do. Basically every night.
My usual spots are this station-front
bath and one other place
called the Yamada Baths.
I don't think I've been to
a public bath since kindergarten...
unless you count taking
visitors to shooting locations.
If you get used to visiting public baths,
you start to recognize the people you meet
and get used to greeting
and talking to them.
I see.
This is hot spring water
straight from the source.
Please do not shut off
the water completely.
Look, I found another gray hair!
Mama, you worry about it too much.
She sure does.
Oh, did you hear? Yut-chan
is pregnant with her second child!
She is?
Yes! And when I took
my girl to go see them...
Th-There's a lot of people here
and I can hear them all talking,
but for some reason,
I actually find it kind of relaxing.
You do? I'm glad you like it!
You know, I don't really think
there's a trick to doing my job.
Huh?
Of course you do need some
knowledge and skills to clean well,
but I don't know,
I think I do this work because I enjoy
seeing my customers satisfied.
On top of that, I really like
this town and the people here.
I think that's a big part of it.
You like the town...
you want people to be satisfied...
It's a little hard to put into words,
but I think that's
what this work means to me.
Now I un...derstand.
You're gonna pass out from the heat!
Atami Station Front
Station Front
Hot Spring
B-But it was very educational.
N-No, wait...
Hatsuayu-san!
Let's get you out of the bath!
That was nice to see yesterday.
I-I'll start going
to the public bath every day
to develop my social skills.
I'm rooting for her.
Wow! Are they shooting something?
Okay, we're good!
Very glad to be of help.
I'll catch you at the bath, okay?
Wash It All Away
Wow, I've never seen
this view of the city before.
Hello, this is Kinme Cleaning.
Kinme-san, w-would you like
to model for a photo shoot?
Huh?
Tourism Economy Division
Office for the Promotion of Tourism / Office for Industrial Development
Office for Media Promotion Strategy
Office of Agriculture, Forestry and Fishery / Agriculture Committee
A local newspaper
publishes a free newsletter,
and they're going to do an article on
"A Relaxing One-Day Girls' Trip."
The newspaper person said they were
searching for local working women
to be the models on the shoot.
I see.
And well, um, I'm going to be one of them,
but they need one more person.
So I thought maybe I could
ask you to do it, Kinme-san.
Huh? You want me to be the other person?
I-I don't know the first
thing about modeling.
I know it's a lot to ask, b-but...
they are offering some compensation
and said they would put ads for
your business in the newsletter for free.
Fall season soon...
Publicity...
Ads...
Free...
U-Um, why don't I tell you
our plans for the day?
All right.
The photographers
went early to get scenery pictures.
We'll meet up with them
and then take pictures around the island
entrance and restaurant district.
After that, we go to a resort facility
and get some shots
at the café and the adventure park.
Then we come back on the last ferry.
That's what we have planned. Yes.
That sounds all right.
The island is actually
very close, isn't it?
Y-Yes! At only twenty-three minutes away,
it's famous as the island closest
to the Tokyo metropolitan area.
Huh. You really do know your stuff.
Huh? W-Well, I am from around here.
Oh. We'll be arriving soon.
Welcome to Hatsushima
Thank you for waiting.
Pleased to meet you.
Why don't we go ahead
and get a shot of you arriving?
Let's go for a relaxing "girls' day trip"
kind of mood today, okay?
Oh, we don't need the helmet, though.
Welcome to Hatsushima
That's the spirit. Great poses too!
Huh? Kinme-san,
you seem kind of used to this.
Um... I've been getting
some practice recently
with an elementary school girl.
Huh?
Okay, why don't we head over
to the restaurant district next?
You haven't had lunch yet, have you?
Huh?
Dining
A-Are you sure we're allowed to eat this?
Absolutely!
The two of us will eat later on.
It glitters! It's all glittery!
I'm local, but I never
get to eat like this!
Yeah.
Well, thank you very much.
Take your time eating, okay?
Ah! The sashimi is so fresh and firm!
And when you bite into the mollusks,
they pop with the flavor of the sea!
It's so delicious!
It's been so long
since I've had a proper meal!
What does Hatsuayu-san usually eat anyway?
I-I have to wear this? You didn't tell me!
I-I'm sorry, Kinme-san.
I thought you might say no if I told you.
Wow.
Hey, what a fantastic figure!
Let's get back to the shoot.
I...
I hope this is all right.
And now a bathing scene, I see.
I-I'm sorry.
Oh! Just like that!
What a lovely expression.
That's it! Thank you both.
I guess we're done.
Huh?
Supermarket Hatsushima
Wait. Where did Kinme-san go?
She was right there a second ago.
Does she know the last ferry leaves soon?
I'll go look for her.
Inn
Kiki
Where could she have gone?
Oh, there she is!
Huh?
Oh, Hatsuayu-san.
U-Um, the boat is leaving soon!
What? Oh, I'm sorry!
This is my fault. I'm sorry for
making you run, Hatsuayu-san!
It's okay!
We will make it, won't we?
Welcome to Hatsushima
Yes! Let's make sure we do.
Oh. There they are!
Hey!
Ugh. I didn't even buy any souvenirs.
I thought we still had plenty of time.
Um, Kinme-san?
Yes?
U-Um, have you ever been
to Hatsushima before?
Huh?
I apologize if I'm mistaken,
but there were a couple of moments
when you seemed to be lost in memories.
Well, I don't actually know.
Huh?
I don't remember anything
from before two years ago.
I had fun today.
So did I! I was supposed to be working,
but I enjoyed myself completely.
Honestly, you had perfect timing
since this was my day off.
Thanks for inviting me!
You're welcome. But you lost a day off.
I can never figure out
how to spend my days off anyway.
Sometimes I end up doing nothing at all.
If you'd like, please feel free
to get in touch on days like that.
Huh? Is that all right with you?
Of course it is! I'm full of
suggestions. After all...
I do work in the tourism division.
Then I'd be happy to!
I could even join you if you'd like.
That would make me even happier!
Translation:
Editing and Typesetting:
Michael Arnold
Ashley Barboza
Quality Control:
Translation Check:
Riley Dalton
Sriram Gurunathan
Episode 9      Power's Out
Next time, "Power's Out."